在上一集里
Previously on "Transformers Prime"...
不 别动也别说话 保存力量
No, don't move or talk. Just power down.
一个新政权统治了你们的世界
A new power dominates your world.
任何针对我的进一步挑衅行为
Any further attempts to attack me
我都会加倍奉还！
will be met with even greater force!
神子！
Miko
不许用手机 你知道规矩的！
no cellphone! You know the rules!
一条短信应该不会有事吧？
One text couldn't hurt, could it?
我明白擎天柱为避免虎子抓到我们 将我们分别传送到不同地点
I realize Optimus sent us all to different locations to make us harder for the 'Cons to find
但如果我们不知道其他人的位置 该怎么找到他们呢？！
but if we don't know where in the world anyone else went, how are we gonna find them?
告诉我你同伙的藏身之地
Tell me the location of your compatriots
用什么手段 花多长时间
no matter what it takes or how long.
集结一支队伍 立刻飞往塞博特恩
Assemble a team and disembark for Cybertron immediately.
他还…活着！
He lives?
震荡波！
Shockwave!
威震天陛下
Lord Megatron.
震荡波
Shockwave!
这可真是一份大大的意外之喜
This is quite an unexpected turn.
我以为你已经在塞博特恩阵亡了
I thought you'd perished on Cybertron.
是啊 是啊 我们都这么以为…
Yes, as... as did we all.
如此轻易地宣告我的死亡 过于草率了
Reports of my demise were greatly premature.
两个汽车人潜入了我在塞博特恩上的实验室
A pair of Autobots infiltrated my facility on Cybertron
破坏了我的太空桥
sabotaging my space bridge.
我尝试进行追击 但却徒劳无功
I gave chase but failed to accurately calculate the outcome.
我在一片废墟之中醒来 完全失明
I awoke in the rubble, blinded.
我很快意识到 我所在的星球已被遗弃
It soon became clear that I was marooned on our dead planet
没有留下任何通信渠道
with no means of communication.
我花费时日修复了自身的伤口 并重新投身于我的实验之中
In time, I repaired my wounds and resumed my experiments.
与世隔绝的我心无旁骛 于是我的研究突飞猛进
The solitude enabled me to make tremendous advances in my research.
直到有一天
Until one day
我的系统检测到不明能量大规模激增…
my instruments detected a massive surge of unidentifiable energy.
于是我前往锈海边缘调查其源头
I traveled to investigate its origin at the edge of the Sea of Rust
在那里我与您的搜索队不期而遇
where I encountered your salvage team
并发现了终极之锁的残片
and the smoldering wreckage of the Omega Lock.
但是这个搜索队并不是为我而来
But this was not the search party I had anticipated so long ago.
所以我有一个问题亟需解答：
Leaving one unanswered question.
为什么将我留下自生自灭 为什么将我遗弃
Why was I left for scrap, abandoned?
为什么？
Why?
那…那场大爆炸…
The... the... the explosion, it...
使核心能量室崩塌了
it collapsed the power-core chamber.
我们只目睹你冲进太空桥入口
The last thing anyone witnessed was you charging into the space-bridge portal.
但没人看见你出来！
No one saw you come back out!
我判定 你的回答…符合逻辑
I find your reply to be... logical.
不过有件事一定会让你非常高兴
But you will be pleased to know that I avenged your seeming demise by
我亲手解决了汽车人飞过山！
personally terminating the Autobot Cliffjumper.
杀个小角色也值得炫耀 红蜘蛛 小心风大闪了舌头
Careful, Starscream. You may dislocate a landing gear patting yourself on the back.
作为威震天的首席副官
As Megatron's First Lieutenant
请允许我欢迎你回归胜利之师
allow me to welcome you back to the winning team.
那么也请允许我来颁布新的指挥体系
And allow me to clarify the new chain of command.
在红蜘蛛保持军事行动指挥权的同时
While Starscream will retain authority over military operations
任命震荡波为我的首席副官 掌管一切科学研究事宜
Shockwave will be my First Lieutenant in charge of all scientific endeavors.
所以 您的意思是我和他平起平坐？
Uh, so you are saying we shall each report directly to you.
正是如此
Affirmative.
毫无逻辑性可言 我的君王
Completely logical, my liege.
嘿 你饿了吗？
Hey, you hungry?
前面有个小镇
There's a town up ahead.
还是算了吧 我的钱包已经瘪了
I'd better not. I'm running low on cash.
至少你不用买汽油
At least you don't have to buy gasoline.
但我还是要停一下 得活动下筋骨…
I'm pulling over anyway. Need to stretch my legs.
啊 舒坦！
Oh, yeah.
阿尔茜 领袖卫队已经四分五裂了
Arcee... team Prime is scattered to the winds.
从目前的情况看 你和我可能是仅有的幸存者
For all we know, you and I could be the only ones left.
我不这么认为 杰克 而且我知道你也一样
I don't believe that, Jack, and I know you don't either.
也许吧
Maybe not.
但是敌我力量相差如此悬殊
But the Decepticons outnumber us 100 to 1.
难道就没有其他汽车人能助我们一臂之力吗？
Aren't there any more Autobots out there who could help?
塞博特恩之战伤亡惨重
The War For Cybertron took a heavy toll.
但当时确实有人乘方舟逃了出去
But there were others who escaped in the ark.
那么…他们在哪儿？
So, where are they?
流落四方…
Scattered to the winds.
所以我们还是把精力集中在赶回贾斯帕
So, let's focus on getting back to Jasper
重聚领袖卫队上吧
and getting team Prime back together.
没有新发现 小蜂
Nada, Bee.
还是那些早就看过的合成图片
Just the same old rubber masks and bad C.G.
网站也许是我们找到其他人的唯一途径了…
But the usualconspiracy websites might be our only chance to...
看！我找到了！
Whoa! I found something!
是救护车！
It's Ratchet!
震荡波明显是在向我示威
Shockwave's toadying is so transparent.
威震天只重视实干家 而非信口开河之徒
Megatron's respect is earned by deeds, not words.
没用！没用！没用！
Useless, useless, useless.
那些讨厌的人类手上有数十亿台照相机
Billions of cameras in the hands of those miserable humans.
总会有人拍到汽车人的…
One of them is bound to catch an Autobot eventually.
瞧啊 瞧啊
Well, well, well.
这是谁呢？
What have we here?
威震天陛下 我找到了点您一定会感兴趣的东西！
Lord Megatron, I have found something of great interest!
这张照片是昨天拍的
The photo was taken yesterday
在森林公园外的废车场
in a junkyard outside Woodland Park.
我得删去救护车 再替换上…
I'd better scrub Ratchet and replace him with...
一个汽车人！
An Autobot!
等等 什么？
Wait, what?
他刚才还在上面的！你们肯定有人看见了！
It was just here! Surely, one of you saw it.
红蜘蛛
Starscream...
有时候你要向声波好好学学
you would do well to take a cue from Soundwave on occasion
别总是一惊一乍的
and keep things to yourself!
给我安静点 这该死的图片
Vow of silence... such a cop-out.
威震天陛下
Lord Megatron
比起这个落后的数据网络 我们的汽车人俘虏无疑是更好的消息来源
surely our Autobot prisoner is a better source of information than this primitive data net.
提醒你一下 震荡波
I will have you know, Shockwave, that I have been grinding Wheeljack down for days.
如果他真知道些什么 早就全盘托出了
If he knew anything, he would've spilled it by now.
的确 有些人确实比其他人更能管住自己的嘴
Again, some prove to be better at holding their tongues than others.
如果你放弃低劣的肉体折磨\N而使用一些尖端的科技 效果可能会更好
Perhaps you would have better results if instead of a club you used a scalpel.
我推荐我的大脑神经接入器
I recommend a cortical psychic patch.
我觉得他不会来了
I don't think he's coming.
别担心 神子
Don't worry, Miko...
每个雷霆救援队员都熟知紧急方案
every Wrecker knows the protocol.
只要他还活着 老千就一定会出现…
Jackie will show. If he's still kicking.
拿出你的看家本领吧 医生
Do your worst, Doc.
我是名雷霆救援队员 我扛得住
I'm a Wrecker. I can take it.
相信我 事实上 你不能
Trust me... you, in fact, cannot.
接入器没能取得任何关于汽车人行踪的新信息
The patch failed to yield any new information on the whereabouts of the Autobots.
嗯…我知道了…
Um... I see...
这么看来 千斤顶已经没有利用价值了
Ah, then it would seem that Wheeljack has outlived his usefulness.
如果您允许 威震天陛下
With your permission, Lord Megatron
我立刻去把他解决掉…
I will see to his immediate termination.
醒醒 雷霆救援队小子
Wake up, Wrecker.
该洗热水澡了！
Time to smelt.
红蜘蛛指挥官想让你清醒过来
Commander Starscream wanted you conscious
这样你就能明白是谁送你上路
so you'd know precisely who ordered your execution.
小红他人呢？
Where is Screamy?
他不敢亲自动手？
Doesn't have the bearings to do this himself?
跳下去！
Jump.
嘿 你会飞吧？
Hey, are you a flier?
好吧 我跳就是了
Okay, I'll jump.
果然能飞！
Thought so!
谢谢你捎我一程
Thanks for the ride.
你就是这么办事的？
This is how you handle things?!
千斤顶不是第一个从红蜘蛛手上逃走的俘虏了
Wheeljack is not the first prisoner to escape Starscream's care.
实际上 主人
Actually, master
是我故意让千斤顶逃走的
I allowed Wheeljack to escape.
你说什么？！
You what?!
但是那个汽车人的一举一动
But the Autobot's every move
一言一语都会在我们的监视之下…
his every word, will be monitored.
因为我在囚犯昏迷不醒时 给他植入了一枚简易跟踪器
Thanks to a simple tracking device implanted while the prisoner was still unconscious
当然 是在某人的大脑神经接入器失败后实施的
following the failed cortical psychic patch.
接下来 我们只需要等一等 看一看 听一听
Now all we have to do is wait, watch, and listen.
一旦他与其他汽车人会合
When the Wrecker reunites with the other Autobots
我的大军就会将他们一网打尽…
my armada will strike.
他应该就在这儿！
He's got to be here.
救护车！救护车 是我 拉夫
Ratchet! Ratchet, it's me, Raf!
嗯…救护车？
Uh, Ratchet?
走开
Go away!
你们打扰到我的休息了！
You're interrupting my power down.
别闹了 救护车 我们需要你的帮助来找到其他人
Come on, Ratchet, we need your help to find the others.
我们是斗不过威震天的！再也不能了
We can't stop Megatron, not anymore.
战争结束了 我们一败涂地
The war is over, and we lost.
你放弃了？
You're giving up?!
我们不能就这么放弃了！
We can't just give up!
那么你告诉我 我们还能做什么！
Then tell me what we can do
没有了通信设备 没有了环陆桥
without communications, without a ground bridge
没有了任何设备或物资…
without a base of operations or resources of any kind!
小蜂说得对
Bee's right.
我们知道红蜘蛛在其单独行动期间 使用过环陆桥
We know Starscream had access to a ground bridge while he was operating solo.
是的 是的 他利用了霸天虎的废弃飞船 先驱号
Yes, yes, he'd clearly been using the derelict Decepticon ship the Harbinger.
但是那有什么用！
What does that have to do with anything?!
那上面可能装满了各种塞博特恩资源
It could be full of Cybertronian tech
既然红蜘蛛已经回到虎子中间了
and it's probably abandoned again now
那飞船可能再次被遗弃了
that Starscream's back with the 'Cons.
好吧 物资再多又能怎么样 如果没有人来…领导我们
Well, resources won't be of much use, not without someone to... lead us.
但这是一个好的开始！
It's a start!
那你们去找别人一起开始吧！
You'll have to start without me.
这场战争已经和我无关了
This is someone else's fight now.
没有别人了 救护车 只有我们！
There is no one else, Ratchet... just us
只有领袖卫队！
just the team.
拜托你们…
Please!
就让我安静地去自生自灭吧
Just let me... rust in peace.
我们走吧 小蜂…
Come on, Bee.
我回来了
I'm back.
我扫描了基地的每个角落
I combed through every square micron of our old base.
也没能找到救护车的医药箱 甚至连条绷带都没有
I couldn't find Ratchet's medical kit, not even a bandage.
卓天越…之锤…
The Forge... of Solus Prime.
也没了 虎子们把基地搜刮得一干二净！
It's gone, too. The 'Cons picked the place clean.
等等
Wait
如果你有了卓天越之锤 就能自我修复了 借领袖之力！
if you had the Forge, you could fix yourself up... power of the Primes.
擎天柱 再坚持一下
Optimus, hang on just a little longer.
锤子一定就在威震天堡垒的某个地方
That hammer's got to be somewhere in Megatron's fortress.
神子？快醒醒！
Miko, wake up.
为什么？
Why?
有人来了
Someone's coming.
不管在哪里 我都听得出这引擎声！
I'd know the hum of that engine anywhere!
哈哈 老千！
Ah! Jackie!
你去哪儿啦 兄弟？
Where have you been, buddy?!
和几个老相识叙了叙旧
Catching up with a few old dance partners.
见到你很高兴 孩子
Good to see you, kid.
看来这附近就只有我们三位雷霆救援队员了
Safe to assume we're the only three Wreckers around?
那我们还等什么？去闹个天翻地覆吧！
So, what are we waiting for? Let's do some damage!
下一步做什么 老千？绕回基地？
What's our next move, Jackie... circle back to base?
没有基地了 虎子们把那儿炸平了
There is no base. 'Cons blasted it to dust.
这些白痴果然被我玩弄于股掌之中…
The dimwit played right into my hands.
集合全体追踪者 我们已锁定敌军位置！
All seekers to the flight deck! We have pinpointed the enemy!
进攻 我的大军！
Attack! My armada.
我们已到达指定坐标 红蜘蛛指挥官
We're at the coordinates, Commander Starscream.
做好准备 他们正在向你们靠近…
Hold fast. They are approaching your position.
目标进入范围
Targets in range?
那就“轰”！
And boom.
是手雷！
Grenade!
他…他耍了我们？！
He... he tricked us!
你怎么知道虎子在你身上装了追踪器？
How'd you know the 'Cons planted a tracker on you?
我猜到虎子们会耍花招
I figured the 'Cons were up to something
于是我对引擎盖下面做了点儿小检查
so I did a little poking around under my hood.
哈哈 不愧是我的老千
Ha! That's my Jackie.
那么 我们的下一步行动是什么？
So, what's our next move?
途中我从钻击号那里抢回了些弹药
I salvaged some munitions from the Jackhammer on my way out.
你觉得刚才动静儿大吗？
You thought that made a loud noise?
好戏才刚开始…
Just wait.
就这样别动 小蜂
Hold it right there, Bee.
然后 启动电源！
And... powering up!
再试试 我们会弄明白的！
Keep trying. We'll figure it out.
不对 不对 不对
Ah-ah-ah.
你们把能量转换装置都调校错了
You're miscalibrating the Energon transducer.
救护车！
Ratchet!
好啦 让开点儿 好让我工作！
Now step out of my way so I can work.
上次事情变糟的时候 擎天柱给了我钥匙芯片！
The last time things looked this bleak, Optimus slipped me that key card...
至少我们还能把它当做希望！
something we could hang our hopes on.
我理解你无助的感觉 杰克
I know you're feeling helpless, Jack.
但你不必把它当做负担
This doesn't need to be your burden.
呆在我身后
Stay behind me.
杰克 我觉得这次我们不需要钥匙芯片了
Jack, I don't think we're gonna need that key card.
来见见通天晓
Meet Ultra Magnus.
你不仅没能消灭汽车人
So, not only did you fail to destroy the Autobots
还壮大了他们的队伍！
but you allowed their number to increase!
难道就没人能取得了汽车人的脑袋吗？
Is there no one who can bring me their heads?!
请允许我向您禀报 威震天陛下
If I may, lord Megatron.
我在塞博特恩的流亡期间
During my exile on Cybertron
我重新启动了一个搁置已久的研究项目
I resumed work on a long-dormant project...
我相信这个项目能解决我们目前的难题
One that I believe may provide a solution to our current problem.
塞博特恩核酸？（类似人类的D.N.A.）
Cyber nucleic acid?
这是构建所有塞博特恩生命的基础
The building blocks of all Cybertronian life.
它源自我在塞星上发掘出的一个标本
This hails from a specimen I excavated upon our planet
而且对其检测的结果很令人满意
and has yielded promising results.
汽车人屡次从我们手中逃脱
The Autobots continue to evade us.
我们怎么能指望培养皿里产生的
What makes you think we can afford to wait for the answer to our prayers to be
…某种试验品呢？
birthed in some Petri dish?
你误解了我的意思
You misunderstand.
实验对象已经被完全培育成功
The subject has been fully cultivated.
我只需将其从塞博特恩的实验室传送过来
It need only be transported from my laboratory on Cybertron.
那还等什么 启动太空桥！
Then by all means, activate the space bridge.
很荣幸向您展示 我的君王
I present to you, my liege...
终极汽车人猎手！
the ultimate Autobot hunter.